Kennedy Osemeke

1 Ilare Close, off International Airport Road, Lagos State, Nigeria

E-mail: kennedvosemeke@gmail.com Phone No: +2348126065307, +2348030843639

CAREER GOAL

To build a career in Communication Engineering and apply knowledge and experience gained over time to the development of an international organization through valuable contributions to the growth of such an organization while developing personal skills.

BIO DATA:

13th September, 1982 Date of Birth:

Country of Birth Nigeria State of Origin Delta State English Language

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- GSM Network Optimization Tools (2G/3G): TEMS, Actix, Panorama, Pioneer, Qualcomm Extensible Diagnostic Monitor, Mapinfo Huawei imanager M2000 and Service Maintenance System.
- GSM Network Planning Tools (2G/3G): U-Net, genex naster, Transdata, Mapinfo (Site see, Grakiter), Google Earth
- Microwave Transmission(Line of Site Tools): PathLoss, Herald, Google Earth
- General Skills: AutoCAD, Matlab, Embedded C Programming, MS Excel, MS Power Point, Opnet.
- SDH, PDH, CISCO Network Design Skills, VLAN, VPN, Firewall, Cryptography, OSPF, MS Project.

RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Northern Innovation Ltd (Belfast, UK)

Contract (Jan to Mar 2015)

- Installation, commissioning and maintenance of borewell water control and monitoring systems for (Hellenic) Coca-Cola Nigeria.
- Experience with sensors, and global Machine to Machine Remote Connectivity (GPRS/3G)

Kenix Consulting Limited (Nigeria) Responsibility: Project Manager

Oct 2012 till date

- - Network Performance analysis and Optimization.
 - Site Survey supervision (RF, Microwave and fiber optic).
 - Analysis of default parameters (Input Power, FD type and Length, Antenna Gain and BW, RF Antenna Height and Link Budget Balancing.)
 - Provision of Technical and Non-Technical Solution
 - Network Planning and Implementation of Enterprise Network for Swift Networks.
 - Planning and implementation of fiber optic connection to business enterprises and residential estates under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
 - Installation of backup UPS power systems for enterprises under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
 - Equipment Shelter Installations for Swift Enterprise Networks

Huaxin Consulting/Huawei Technologies Limited Dec 2009—Jan 2011 Responsibilities: Team Lead Network Planning/Optimization Engineer (Multilinks NOC)

- Network Planning, Optimization and Resource Parameter Adjustments (at NOC) of Telcom/Multi-Links network.
- Network Monitoring and Fault Isolation using Huawei imanager M2000 and Service Maintenance System.
- Analysis of network performance based on statistical counters, network recordings, Geolocation tools and drive test data.
- Provision of preventive and corrective maintenance suggestions to customer.
- Preparation of daily, weekly and monthly Performance Reports with extensive use of MS Word, Excel, Power Point and Access.
- Drive Test, Low level optimization, Engineering Parameter Adjustments and network optimization for GSM 2G, GPRS, EDGE, 3G, CDMA 1X and EVDO (voice and data).
- Planning and preparation of BTS Configuration Script.
- Excellent Leadership and Project Management skills.
- Ability to work with little or no supervision.

Huaxin Consulting/Huawei Technologies Limited (Etisalat Project) July 2008 - Dec 2009 Responsibilities: Project Engineer (RNPO)

- Planning and optimization for 2G, 2.5G and 3G Network for Etisalat.
- Technical site survey and design for new sites (Power Systems, RF, Microwave and Civil Works) using autoCAD.
- Site Verification (Power, RF and Microwave).
- Microwave Transmission planning.
- Frequency, Neighbor List and LAC planning for Etisalat.
- Coordinate and supervise the activities of optimization and drive test engineers.
- Resolve escalated customer complaints.
- Drive Test, Network tuning, parameter adjustment, low level optimization for 2G and 3G.
- Strong analytical skill and initiatives.
- Good inter-personal and communication skills.

Huaxin Consulting

Jan 2008 - June 2008

• 6 months Telecommunications and Power Systems Engineering training

PROFFESIONAL QUALIFICATIONS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification (2009)
- Institution of Engineering and Technology (MIET)
- Project Management Institute (PMI).

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

July, 2012 University of Portsmouth, United Kingdom (IET Academic Partner).

MSc. Communication Systems Engineering (Distinction, and award for best MSc. project 2012).

2001-2006 University of Benin

BEng. Electrical/Electronic Engineering (Second Class Upper Division)

<u>Major Courses</u>

- ➤ Power Generation, Transmission and Distribution
- > Telecommunication and Information Technology
- > Electronic Engineering.

PROJECTS/ RESEARCH UNDERTAKEN

- Drive test and optimization for Multilinks/Telcom for Kano, Kaduna and Warri
- Site selection and Technical Site survey for Visafone Nigeria.
- Optimization for Etisalat Northern region of Nigeria.
- Technical site survey for Etisalat Nigeria. Installation, commissioning and maintenance of borewell water control and monitoring systems for (Hellenic) Coca-cola Nigeria
- ECG Data Compression and transmission for Telemedicine using Embedded C Programming for Micro-Controllers (MSc Project)
- Planning and implementation of fiber optic connection to business enterprises and estates under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.
- Installation of backup UPS power systems for enterprises under the Swift Enterprise Network Solutions.

HOBBIES/INTEREST:

- Playing chess, tennis, swimming
- Travelling

REFERENCES

Tim Burch

Engineering Manager (Northern Innovation Ltd.) Maryland Industrial Estate 286 Ballygowan Road Moneyreagh Belfast BT23 6BL

Email: tim@northerninnovation.com

Mr. Zhou

MD, Huaxin Consulting Nigeria Limited 27/28 Agodogba Street, Parkview Estate, Ikoyi, Lagos zhougx@hxdi.com +234-1-4620370

Mr Hari Krisna

Huawei Technologies Limited Multilinks /Telcom NMC Project Manager hari@huawei.com +2347029588871

Dr Alan Hewitt

Senior Lecturer
School of Engineering
Anglesea Building, Anglesea Road, Portsmouth,
United Kingdom
Hants, PO1 3DJ
alan.hewitt@port.ac.uk